# Izaac Laundry Mottiar

# 3A Mechatronics Engineering University of Waterloo

905-341-0341 imlaundr@uwaterloo.ca LinkedIn

I'm currently in my third year of Mechatronics Engineering at the University of Waterloo, specializing in embedded systems and software development. Feel free to explore my portfolio to learn more about the projects I've worked on.

# Technical Skills

**Programming:** Fluent in Python, C/C++, MATLAB, MS Excel, Ladder Logic, React and CSS.

Mechanical: Skilled in AutoCAD, SolidWorks, and Fusion 360, with experience in 3D Printing and Machining Electrical: Experienced in circuit and PCB design, leveraging STM32, Arduino, and Raspberry Pi platforms.

# Experience

#### Hardware Test Intern — StandardBioTools, Markham ON.

Sept. 2024 - Dec. 2024

- Conducted lifecycle testing by integrating a pneumatic actuator and camera system to automate physical testing and validate results.
  - $\circ~$  Developed a script to manage the process, ensuring autonomous operation and automated result collection.
- Analyzed and certified five gas manifolds by performing leak checks, pressure sensor accuracy tests, and MFC precision and resolution analysis.
  - Authored Project Change Requests to address design issues and improve designs.
  - $\circ\,$  Led supplier meetings to resolve MFC inconsistencies and streamline communication.
  - o Developed Python scripts to automate data collection for pressure sensors, flow rates, and leak detection.

## Manufacturing Engineering Intern — Greenhouse Juice Co. Mississauga ON.

Jan. 2024 - April. 2024

- Integrated the NIMCO Gable Top machine into production, increasing juice production by 10%.
  - Engineered custom jigs and developed UV monitoring protocols for precise liquid flow control.
  - Created an SOP and trained operators for consistent implementation.
- Developed a hydrogen peroxide detection system using OAK-1 PoE and Raspberry Pi 5, enabling real-time monitoring, LED updates, and automated Excel logging.
- Monitored machinery data, performed daily water titration tests, and tracked gas, water, and electricity consumption to optimize resource usage.

#### Controls Specialist Intern — JMP Solutions, Oakville ON.

May. 2023 - Sept. 2023

- Developed and programmed PLCs to regulate the drive speed of two KOBM slurry pumps for ArcelorMittal Dofasco, optimizing operational efficiency.
- Collaborated closely with the Vice President and General Manager of Integration and Engineering Services to successfully complete a corporate-wide file management initiative.
- Drafted nine x-axis motion and nine z-axis motion drives to control multi-cut saws used for cutting exhaust pipes of varying lengths for ArcelorMittal Dofasco.

#### Chassis Team Member — University of Waterloo Formula Motorsports

Sept. 2023 - April. 2023

- Crafted an aluminum hose valve on the lathe and precision-milled various brackets.
- Designed and fabricated a cover for the radiator using SolidWorks and waterjet cutting techniques.

### Education

University of Waterloo — Candidate for Bachelors of Mechatronics Engineering.

Secondary School — Graduated with honours diploma and 98% average

Sept. 2022 - Present Sept. 2018 - June. 2022

Outside of my professional pursuits, I am actively engaged in various university intramural sports, including soccer, basketball, and slo-pitch. I also enjoy a wide range of physical activities such as tennis, bouldering, racing, and backpacking. When time permits, I unwind by reading, as well as playing board and video games, which allow me to foster creativity and strategic thinking.